# **KURAVI NIHARIKA**

Chennai, Tamil Nadu-603002 | +91 8179753011 | niharika.kuravii@gmail.com

## **Objective:**

I am a MEAN/MERN based full stack programmer with an year of experience working in client applications. I have contributed to couple enterprise level platform development through UI and thoroughly enjoy taking up technical challenges. Also, I have a strong inclination towards application of data structures, algorithms and patterns for solving technical problems. I have worked on creating solutions for Machine Learning problems as well and would love to take up an opportunity on similar lines. My aim is to conjoin my professional experience with my passion for solving problems through my next opportunity.

## **Skills & Technologies:**

- Node
- Express
- Angular
- React
- Redux
- MongoDB
- Material UI
- MicroServices

- HTML5, CSS3, JQuery
- Bootstrap4
- AJAX
- Core Java
- Aware of various Machine learning concepts, Gatsby, Sass.

# **Work Experience**

From Nov 2019 – Present

Systems Engineer specialist | Infosys Ltd | Chennai

#### **Nomination Management Portal:**

Nomination platform is a web based application which manages end-to-end processes involved in delivering orders of client.

Major technologies used: React 16, Redux, Material UI, Flex Box, .Net Core MVC, Azure.

I work as a UI developer in this project and primarily responsible for-

- 1. Developing reusable UI components and handling API interactions.
- 2. Taking part in Creating design plan for upcoming sprints.
- 3. Unit testing components and maintaining flows in application.
- 4. Proactively participating in various scrum ceremonies.

### Major work items:

- 1. Developing components using Redux and helping team understanding same,
- 2. Coordinating with team and developing design plan.
- 3. Creation of various wrapper components which are reused in application.
- 4. Configuration of Azure resources with application.

### **Payment Gateway Connector:**

Payment gateway connector is a standalone application which manages payment gateway communication of ecommerce app. The connector app customizes data and handles exception by acting as bridge between both the apps.

Major technologies used — Nodejs, Expressjs, Typescript, Serverless, AWS lambda.

Major work items-

- 1. Development of application to handle different types of transaction.
- 2. Testing the application for various scenarios.

### **Tender Management Portal:**

Tender Platform is a web based application meant to store and manage details of clients and their requirements for any project(s). The platform calculates appropriate budget and effort based on the input set of requirements that are run against a set of rules.

Major technologies used- Angular 9, Flex Box, Angular Material, RxJs store, .Net Core MVC,

I worked as a UI developer in this project and I am primarily responsible for-

- 1. Development of views and components that represent different flows of the application,
- 2. Improvement and maintenance of existing flows in the application,
- 3. Unit testing and code coverage,
- 4. Handling API responses and Azure interactions with the front end of the application.

Major work items-

- 1. Development of components with Material Design and Flex Box and helping team with understanding the same.
- 2. Upgrade of Angular framework to Angular 9
- 3. Configuration of Azure resources with application.

### **Graduate Apply Portal:**

Graduate Apply Portal is a web based platform that connects aspiring graduate/postgraduate students in UK to different institutions and simplifies the process of admissions.

I worked for this project as a full stack developer with primary responsibility towards the development, maintenance and unit testing of the front end application and taking up backend tasks for API creation and improvements on a need basis.

Major technologies used- Angular 8 with Material design, NgRx store, Express, Node, MongoDB

### Major work items-

- 1. Development of 'Register & Login' set of screens for with focus on Material Design usage.
- 2. Development of interactive Form filling feature for selected candidates with focus on validation, routing and transfer of state in UI.
- 3. Development of API for accepting a search filter from UI and providing filtered responses along with aggregated results.

## From July 2019- Nov 2019

Systems Engineer specialist Trainee | Infosys Ltd | Chennai

During this period I have explored MEAN and MERN stack technologies along with developing projects to experience hands-on challenges.

#### **E-commerce Portal:**

E-commerce is a web based application for both buyers and sellers, which could migrate marketing system to online for growth of business and accessibility of user. I worked as a full stack developer with UI development using React 16 along with redux for UI state management. The Api is developed with Express 4.1 by using MongoDB at database and Mongoose as ORM. Api are developed using Micro services. UI is made responsive using Bootstrap4.

## **Other Projects:**

### From Jan 2019- May 2019

## Counterfeit note detector:

It is a mobile app for counterfeit note detection developed using transfer learning of Machine Learning techniques. Data augmentation techniques are used for generating large datasets along and Convolution Neural Networks is implemented using MobileNet model which used SVM classifier . The model is later integrated with flutter project and developed as a mobile app.

## **Education:**

- B.Tech | Sree vidyanikethan Engineering College | 2015-2019
- Computer science and Engineering
- Intermediate from Narayana Junior college, Nellore.
- Schooling from Modern school, Nellore

## **Certifications**

- Infosys Certified Angular Professional
- Infosys Certified React Professional
- Microsoft Certified in Azure Fundamentals
- Microsoft Certified Azure Developer Associate

# **Awards & Recognitions**

- High Performer during training
- Insta award for bottom line responsibility taken on delivery of crucial functionality in Tender Platform.
- Reap award for playing crucial role in Best Project of organization.

## **Extra Details:**

- Current CTC 5 Lakhs INR
- Expected CTC 9 Lakhs INR
- Notice Period –90 days (Negotiable to 45 days)